[Music]
Hello friends, I am Jignesh Parmar, and I
welcome you all to my channel.
Today, in this video, we are going to learn about
ICC Life Insurance's guaranteed
return plan, the ICC Prudential Guaranteed
Pension Plan, Flexi.
Friends, this is a very good plan
for retired investors who need a pension. To
understand this plan thoroughly, it is very important for you to watch this video till the end.
If you have
n't subscribed to the channel yet, please
subscribe so that
you can get more such information as soon as possible. Friends,
such potential guaranteed pension plan,
Flexi, is a non-linked, meaning it has
no connection with equity, and is non-
participating, meaning it gives a guaranteed return. That is, it is a
pension plan.
Now, let's talk about its features.
Friends, in this plan, you are given the
option of guaranteed return as well as return of premium.
In this plan, you are
given about 7 different options, in which
you can choose any option for your pension.
You can take the amount monthly, quarterly,
yearly for this, and the SEBI date is
a very good option.  If this is a feature, then with the help of this feature
you can take the amount of annuity on your desired date.
Friends, if you have
additional funds, then you can also get a top up done in this plan. So
friends, these were the
features of the plan. Now we will get a brief
information about this plan. So here there are
two NUT options - with return of
premium and without return of premium. There are
about five
options in the with return of premium and two options in the without return of premium. There are
two options in the guaranteed edition. The
minimum age of entry is 40 years
for primary and 30 years
for secondary. The maximum age of entry is
70 years. The premium payment term is from five
to 15 years. The deferment period is
one year for five to 15 years. The premium
payment frequency is annual, half yearly,
monthly. The minimum value given is ₹12000 per annum
i.e. 1000 per month and the maximum NUT is
subject to board approval. The NUT pay
outtake frequency is annual, half yearly.  Yearly
Quarterly Monthly So friends, this was a little
information, now we will take information about all its options
one by one, the
first option is Single Life without Return
of Premium, friends, under this option
any policy holder has to
pay money till the premium payment term and after that
after the deferment period,
pension will start getting paid and it will be paid
till the death of A Newton, so let us understand this with the help
of an example, friends, in this example there is
a Newton whose next 50 years is the
premium payment term, five years, the estimated
premium is 10 lakhs, the deferment period is
10 years and the total premium will be paid 50 lakhs, so it
means that this investor will
pay a total of 50 lakhs from 50 to 55 years and the deferment
period is 10 years, which means that here
his money is being paid till the age of 60 and
from the age of 61, he will
start getting Rs. 54034 every year and he will get it till the
death of the annual payer,
if this money is halved then
he gets two lakhs  67554 rupees
quarterly,
1124066 rupees and monthly 43718 rupees.
Talking about death benefit here, if the
policy holder dies during the deferment period, then
he gets deferment benefit and that death
benefit has two options. The first option is the
premium paid by you
plus one more guaranteed addition and the second option
is 105% of the total premium paid by you. This means that
whichever is higher of these two options, the
investor will normally get the death benefit and
after death during the deferment period,
no death benefit is available. The second option
is Joint Life without Return of Premium.
This option is also exactly like the first option, the
only difference between the two is that it has
two dependents. If the first
insured dies, then the NUT
amount starts getting credited to the second insured
and this second insured will keep getting this amount
till his death. Here, the entry of the second insured is
ahead. In the example, it has been for a minimum of 30 years.  If we
take information, then if a 50 year old
investor invests Rs. 50 lakh, then he
starts getting Rs. 484710 every annuity
and if he dies, then the
other person starts getting this amount and
in this plan also the debt benefit is also the same, it is just that
if there is
death in the deferment period of both the investors, then the
nominee will get the debt benefit. Now
talking about the third option, Single Life with
Return of Premium, this option is exactly
like the first option, the only difference in it is that
whenever there is death in the deferment period,
then his nominee gets
back whatever premium he had paid. So, if we take an example, if the investment is for
five years
and he has invested Rs. 50 lakh, then the other
person will get Rs. 488 every year
and whenever he dies, then normally he will
get Rs. 50 lakh benefit. The
fourth option is Joint Life with Return of
Premium, this option is exactly like the second option.  The
only difference is that here
after the death of both, the nominee will get
back the premium amount. For example, if the
PPT is for five years, if it is
done at ₹50000, the annuitant will get
₹45528 every year, the first annuitant will also get it,
after his death the second annuitant will get it and
after his death also the annuitant will get ₹50 lakh. Now the
fifth option is single life i.e. return of
premium on critical illness and permanent
disability due to accident and death.
Friends, in this option, the nominee has to
pay the money in the PPT and will get the benefit till the deferment period,
but after that,
in the deferment period, whenever he is diagnosed with any of these
critical illnesses or there is
permanent disability due to any accident
or there is death, then
whatever premium amount is, the nominee will
get back the premium amount. If we continue the example, then
here after paying ₹50 lakh in 5 years,
he will get ₹466244 every year
and also his  If death occurs due to a
critical reason, the sum assured will be
returned to the nominee free of cost, but if any of these is a
critical illness insurance or
disability due to an accident, the death insurance is
required. The sixth option is single life and
booster payout. Friends, in this plan, a
policy is available like a normal plan, but
ultimately, the policyholder gets a booster to meet some unplanned or unplanned
expenses, that is,
extra money is available,
and there are some conditions that after the tiffin period, the
booster payout can be received only from the fifth year,
and that too will be
available only after every five years, and the
booster payout will be available only five times, and A Newton can get only
10% of the premium paid
as booster payout. If we continue the example, if a
premium of Rs 50 lakh has been paid for five years, then
every year the NDTV payment will start at Rs
418287, and the first booster will be available at the age of 65,
which will be 10%, that is, Rs 5 lakh, after that,
77 80 more  At 85 years and when the
patient dies here, then normally he will
get Rs. 2500000 because he has already received Rs.
2500000 in the form of booster payouts at the end of 5-5 years
and the net benefit in this is something like this, the
benefit benefit of the deferment period is different
and the benefit after the deferment period
is different, the only difference is that the amount of
net pay done will be as much as the death benefit
and whichever option
is the highest, that much net benefit will be
available here, all the seven options are single life
accelerated health booster, so friends,
in this option, the patient gets NDTV
but if the health condition of the patient is
not good and he is facing problem in normal routine i.e.
daily living activities, then
extra amount will be given for all those activities and those daily
activities are
washing, dressing, transfer, toilet in
feeding and mobility, so
if annual payment is made for such routine activities  If
they are facing any problem, then the
insured will get an extra amount to
compensate for it. For example, if we continue for
five years, PPT is done from 50 years onwards and premium of Rs. 50 lakh is paid, then
here the annuitant will
get Rs. 411576 every year and suppose if any kind of health problem is diagnosed at the age of 65, then he will get Rs. 5
lakh every year for the next 5 years and after his death, the
nominee will get Rs. 25 lakh. Here
you have to keep in mind that the accelerator
health booster which is available is available only for 5 years
and in this way death benefit is also
available before the firm period and
after the deferment period. This was the complete
information about these options. Now we will take some information about
extra benefits. In this, the
first option is high premium benefit.
Friends, if you pay a little more premium,
then you get extra benefit in NBT.
If you pay Rs. 50000 annual
premium in 7 years PPT.
You get an extra benefit of 1.5%,
3.5% for ₹1 lakh to ₹2 lakh, and
4.5% for annual premiums of more than 5 years. So,
if you have taken a deferment period of 11 to 15 years
and are paying a premium of more than ₹5 lakh,
you will
get an extra benefit of ₹8.5 lakh. Another option is
here where you can also avail the benefit of deferment of premium. You
can also top up your annuity amount and there is the feature of SEBI date.
You
can also take annuity amount on any date of your choice, such as your
child's birthday anniversary. In this way,
you can also take a loan
on your policy on any date. However, this option
is not available for the first and second options
because it is not available for single life without return of
premium and joint life without return of
premium. What will happen if you do
not pay the premium? If
you stop paying the premium within the first two years,
your policy will be cancelled.
You will not get any benefit
if you have paid for more than 2 years, so that the
policy will be a paid up policy and
you will get reduced benefit, meaning
you will be given benefit according to the premium you have paid. You
can also revive your policy but with some terms
and conditions. You can also get your policy revoked, there are
some terms and conditions for that too.
Here you can
also get suicide benefit after one year and apart from that, you will
also get all these facilities like free look period, grace period policy.
Friends, this was all the information about ICC
Prudential Guaranteed Pension Plan Flexi of ICC Prudential Life Insurance.
So, before buying this policy,
take complete information about its plans and its options so that
you know which plan is
suitable for you. So friends, if you
liked this video, then like,
comment, share it and if you have
not subscribed to the channel yet, then like and
subscribe to the channel so that
you get more such information as soon as possible.
[Music]